{
  "title": "2.12",
  "definitions": {
    "CONTRACT": {
      "word": "CONTRACT",
      "phonetic": "(kon'-trakt)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">an agreement </p><p>A CONTRACT is a legal agreement between two or more persons or companies to do something. For a CON- TRACT to be <i class=“def-ital\">legal</i>, both sides have to state that they will do something. For example, a person agrees to perform a service and a company agrees to pay him for it. If either side fails to live up to the agreement, it could be sued.</p><p>“She signed a CONTRACT with the company stating that she would do the job in six months for ten thou- sand dollars.” </p><p>“He said he didn’t have to do the work because it wasn’t in his CONTRACT with them.” </p><p>“Our CONTRACT expires at midnight. Unless we agree on a new one, no one will go to work.”</p>"
    },
    "SLITHER": {
      "word": "SLITHER",
      "phonetic": "(sliTH'-ÔøΩr)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to slide, slip </p><p>SLITHER is one of many words that begin with the letters <i class=“def-ital\">sl</i> and which have the meaning of <i class=“def-ital\">slip or slide</i>. The motion in SLITHER is like that of a snake sliding over the ground. To SLITHER is to slide along in a side-to-side way. </p><p>“The snake SLITHERED away into the bushes.” </p><p>“The children SLITHERED across the ice on their backsides.” </p><p>SLITHERY, the adjective form, means slippery. </p><p>“The wet soap was SLITHERY and hard to hold.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: SLITHERY, adj.</p>"
    },
    "LEGISLATOR": {
      "word": "LEGISLATOR",
      "phonetic": "(lej'-is-lA-tÔøΩr)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a lawmaker </p><p>LEGISLATOR comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">law</i>, which is also the source of <i class=“def-ital\">legal</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">legitimate</i>. A LEGISLATOR is a person who makes laws, a member of a lawmaking body like the Senate or the House of Representatives. </p><p>“She was one of the three LEGISLATORS to oppose the president’s plan.\"</p><p>A LEGISLATURE is the body of persons who make laws. To LEGISLATE is to make laws. LEGISLATION is the act of making laws, or the laws made. On the Pretest, many people choose judge as the synonym for LEGISLATOR. But a <i class=“def-ital\">judge</i> belongs to a totally separate branch of government. Judges interpret the laws that LEGISLATORS make.</p><p> Other forms of the word: LEGISLATE, v. </p><p>LEGISLATION, n. </p><p>LEGISLATURE, n.</p>"
    },
    "PARALLEL": {
      "word": "PARALLEL",
      "phonetic": "(par'-ÔøΩlel)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">going in the same direction, side by side; similar </p><p>PARALLEL lines are lines which go in the same direction and, even if they went on forever, would never meet. So PARALLEL is used about things which run side by side without crossing each other. </p><p>“The two roads ran PARALLEL to each other for several miles before they branched off.” </p><p>In general use PARALLEL means “having the same course, nature, or tendency,” <i class=“def-ital\">similar</i>.n“There was a PARALLEL increase in both poverty and crime in that city.”</p>"
    },
    "LOGICAL": {
      "word": "LOGICAL",
      "phonetic": "(loj'-i-kÔøΩI",
      "pos": "or",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">loj-ÔøΩkÔøΩI) adj.: agreeing with </p><p>LOGIC, reasonable LOGIC is sound reasoning. </p><p>“We all admired the LOGIC of her arguments.” </p><p>“There wasn’t much LOGIC in what he said.” </p><p>LOGICAL means “having LOGIC, according to LOGIC,” <i class=“def-ital\">reasonable</i>.  </p><p>“His speech sounded impressive, but it wasn’t very LOGICAL. When you really studied it, it didn’t make any sense at all.” </p><p>“The LOGICAL place to start looking for the missing pen is wherever you saw it last.” </p><p>“She was a LOGICAL person. She never jumped to conclusions, and always had a good reason for what- ever she did.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: LOGIC, n.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-al</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "FIENDISH": {
      "word": "FIENDISH",
      "phonetic": "(fEn'-dish)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">devilish, cruel and wicked </p><p>A FIEND was originally an enemy, the opposite of a friend. From this it came to be used only about devils, who are the enemies of mankind. Now it is used generally about any very cruel or wicked person. </p><p>“He must have been a FIEND to murder them all in cold blood.” </p><p>Something which is FIENDISH is appropriate to a FIEND; it is cruel and savage.  </p><p>“He took a FIENDISH delight in pulling the wings off flies.” </p><p>“With a FIENDISH laugh he jumped out at them from behind the bush.” </p><p>“The FIENDISH old woman frightened little chil- dren.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: FIEND, n.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-ish</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "MONARCH": {
      "word": "MONARCH",
      "phonetic": "(mon'-grk)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a ruler, a king or queen </p><p>A MONARCH is someone, like a king or queen, who is the ruler of a kingdom or empire. </p><p>“Queen Victoria was the MONARCH of the British Empire for many years.” </p><p>“He dreamed of being a MONARCH and having power over millions of people.” A MONARCHY is a government ruled by a MONARCH. “England is a limited MONARCHY. Its king or queen has very little real power any more.” Other forms of the word: MONARCHY, n.</p>"
    },
    "RECOLLECT": {
      "word": "RECOLLECT",
      "phonetic": "(re-kg-lekt')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to remember, recall, bring to mind again </p><p>To RECOLLECT is to remember, to call to mind. RECOLLECT usually suggests more effort than remember. </p><p>“He tried to RECOLLECT how he had fixed the television set before.” </p><p>“Do you RECOLLECT what their telephone number is?” </p><p>“I can’t quite RECOLLECT what the score of that game was.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: RECOLLECTION, n.</p>"
    },
    "SNICKER": {
      "word": "SNICKER",
      "phonetic": "(snik'-gr)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to laugh, giggle </p><p>The word SNICKER is both a verb and a noun. SNICKER means to <i class=“def-ital\">laugh</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">giggle</i>, usually in an embarrassed or disrespectful fashion, as at a dirty joke. </p><p>“They SNICKERED at the cartoons in the magazine.” </p><p>“The speaker was annoyed at the SNICKERS from the back of the room.” </p><p>Usage: SNICKER is sometimes spelled snigger.</p>"
    },
    "VERDICT": {
      "word": "VERDICT",
      "phonetic": "(ver'-dikt)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a decision, judgment </p><p>n law, a VERDICT is a decision reached, by a jury for example, about the guilt or innocence of someone who is on trial. </p><p>“The jury returned a VERDICT of guilty on all the charges against him.” </p><p>“The jury’s VERDICT was that the defendant had to pay us the ten thousand dollars he owed us.” </p><p>VERDICT can also be used about any kind of decision or opinion, especially one reached after carefully weighing the evidence. </p><p>“The doctors’ VERDICT was that he only had six months to live.” </p><p>“The voters will return their VERDICT on the mayor’s performance in the election this fall.”</p>"
    },
    "BARBARIC": {
      "word": "BARBARIC",
      "phonetic": "(bahr-bar'-ik)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">savage, uncivilized </p><p>A BARBARIAN is a person who is wild and almost completely uncivilized. It is said that the ancient Greeks coined the word because foreigners who didn’t speak Greek sounded as if they were saying nothing but <i class=“def-ital\">barbar</i>. BARBARIC and BARBAROUS are similar adjectives re- lated to BARBARIAN. BARBARIC means “of or like BARBARIANS,” <i class=“def-ital\">wild, savage, uncivilized</i>.  </p><p>“The way they treat prisoners in that jail is BARBARIC.” </p><p>“The wild, BARBARIC music drove the audience wild.” </p><p>BARBARIC is frequently confused with ancient. Ancient people were not all BARBARIC, however; and BARBARIC people still exist today. </p><p>Other forms of the word: BARBARIAN, n., adj. </p><p>BARBAROUS, adj.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-ic</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "DAMAGE": {
      "word": "DAMAGE",
      "phonetic": "(dam'-ij)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">harm, hurt, injury </p><p>DAMAGE is injury that causes some kind of loss, as in property, value, or usefulness. </p><p>“The storm caused a great deal of DAMAGE along the coast.” </p><p>“There was little DAMAGE to our car as a result of the accident.” </p><p>DAMAGE is also a verb, meaning to cause harm to. </p><p>“Those false rumors DAMAGED his reputation.” </p><p>“The early frost DAMAGED our crops.” </p><p>“His house was DAMAGED slightly when it was struck by lightning.”</p>"
    },
    "FESTIVE": {
      "word": "FESTIVE",
      "phonetic": "(fes'-tiv)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">joyous, merry </p><p>FESTIVE is related to the word feast, which is a large, splendid meal. Something which is FESTIVE is appropriate to a feast or a similar happy time. </p><p>“He wore his fancy shirt only on FESTIVE occasions\"—that is, only at joyous times like Christmas, weddings, holidays, etc. </p><p>“Winning the championship put everyone in a FESTIVE mood; we celebrated all night.” </p><p>A FESTIVAL is an occasion for feasting or celebrating. </p><p>“The summer FESTIVAL was so much fun that we are going again next year.” </p><p>FESTIVITY is FESTIVE activity, merrymaking. </p><p>“The FESTIVITIES began with boat races and a singalong.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: FESTIVAL, n. </p><p>FESTIVITY, n.</p>"
    },
    "SUSCEPTIBLE": {
      "word": "SUSCEPTIBLE",
      "phonetic": "(sÔøΩ-sep'-tÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">easily affected, easily influenced, sensitive </p><p>SUSCEPTIBLE means easily affected or influenced. </p><p>“Many people are SUSCEPTIBLE to the cold; they seem to sneeze and sniffle all winter long.” </p><p>“We feared that our defenses were SUSCEPTIBLE to an attack from the rear.” </p><p>The word is often used about people whose emotions or decisions are easily influenced. </p><p>“The king is SUSCEPTIBLE to flattery. If you flatter him, he’ll give you almost anything you want.” </p><p>“He is very stubborn; he is not even SUSCEPTIBLE to reason.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: SUSCEPTIBILITY, n. </p><p>Usage: SUSCEPTIBLE is usually followed by <i class=“def-ital\">to</i>.</p>"
    },
    "DREAD": {
      "word": "DREAD",
      "phonetic": "(dred)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to fear greatly, be terrified of </p><p>To DREAD something is to have a deep fear of it. DREAD is especially used about things that are going to happen in the future. </p><p>“I DREAD going to this party. I never have a good time at large parties.” </p><p>“Sally DREADED the math exam, but she ended up doing well on it.\"</p><p>DREAD is also a noun, meaning great fear. </p><p>“He has a DREAD of going into a dark house all by himself.” </p><p>“No one could cure her of her DREAD of spiders.”</p>"
    }
  },
  "id": "12",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Read the CONTRACT.",
          "answers": [
            "report",
            "instructions",
            "agreement",
            "decision",
            "statements"
          ],
          "word": "CONTRACT",
          "correct": "agreement"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Watched them SLITHER.",
          "answers": [
            "fall",
            "slide",
            "run",
            "jump",
            "fly"
          ],
          "word": "SLITHER",
          "correct": "slide"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were LEGISLATORS.",
          "answers": [
            "leaders",
            "teachers",
            "judges",
            "lawyers",
            "lawmakers"
          ],
          "word": "LEGISLATOR",
          "correct": "lawmakers"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Running PARALLEL.",
          "answers": [
            "side by side",
            "to a point",
            "across",
            "opposite",
            "at angles"
          ],
          "word": "PARALLEL",
          "correct": "side by side"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Completely LOGICAL.",
          "answers": [
            "reasonable",
            "wonderful",
            "serious",
            "true",
            "stupid"
          ],
          "word": "LOGICAL",
          "correct": "reasonable"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FIENDISH plans.",
          "answers": [
            "childish",
            "wonderful",
            "poor",
            "difficult",
            "devilish"
          ],
          "word": "FIENDISH",
          "correct": "devilish"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "True MONARCH.",
          "answers": [
            "servant",
            "owner",
            "father",
            "ruler",
            "kingdom"
          ],
          "word": "MONARCH",
          "correct": "ruler"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I can't RECOLLECT.",
          "answers": [
            "win",
            "remember",
            "say",
            "forget",
            "refuse"
          ],
          "word": "RECOLLECT",
          "correct": "remember"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He SNICKERS.",
          "answers": [
            "groans",
            "sighs",
            "sneezes",
            "shouts",
            "laughs"
          ],
          "word": "SNICKER",
          "correct": "laughs"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "What is your VERDICT?",
          "answers": [
            "belief",
            "charge",
            "decision",
            "request",
            "excuse"
          ],
          "word": "VERDICT",
          "correct": "decision"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BARBARIC people.",
          "answers": [
            "ugly",
            "stupid",
            "friendly",
            "ancient",
            "savage"
          ],
          "word": "BARBARIC",
          "correct": "savage"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Aware of the DAMAGE.",
          "answers": [
            "dirt",
            "harm",
            "rubbish",
            "problem",
            "danger"
          ],
          "word": "DAMAGE",
          "correct": "harm"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "In a FESTIVE mood.",
          "answers": [
            "friendly",
            "nervous",
            "merry",
            "sad",
            "generous"
          ],
          "word": "FESTIVE",
          "correct": "merry"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They are all SUSCEPTIBLE.",
          "answers": [
            "untrustworthy",
            "simple minded",
            "strong willed",
            "likeable",
            "easily affected"
          ],
          "word": "SUSCEPTIBLE",
          "correct": "easily affected"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We DREAD them.",
          "answers": [
            "laugh at",
            "demand",
            "hope for",
            "refuse",
            "greatly fear"
          ],
          "word": "DREAD",
          "correct": "greatly fear"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do at least two people have to be involved in a CONTRACT?",
          "word": "CONTRACT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If you dropped an iron, would it SLITHER to the ground?",
          "word": "SLITHER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a senator a LEGISLATOR?",
          "word": "LEGISLATOR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are the sides of a triangle PARALLEL?",
          "word": "PARALLEL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a LOGICAL person make mistakes?",
          "word": "LOGICAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is an angel FIENDISH?",
          "word": "FIENDISH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is the United States a MONARCHY?",
          "word": "MONARCH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can most people RECOLLECT the names of their brothers and sisters?",
          "word": "RECOLLECT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people often SNICKER when someone makes a fool of himself?",
          "word": "SNICKER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do only juries reach VERDICTS?",
          "word": "VERDICT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would someone who kills children be called BARBARIC?",
          "word": "BARBARIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do floods cause DAMAGE?",
          "word": "DAMAGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most people have fun at a FESTIVAL?",
          "word": "FESTIVE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it good for an athlete to be SUSCEPTIBLE to injury?",
          "word": "SUSCEPTIBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do some people DREAD flying in an airplane?",
          "word": "DREAD",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "The judge ruled that the CONTRACT was legal, and that everyone who signed it had to do what it stated.",
          "word": "CONTRACT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The men SLITHERED through the small tunnel to escape from prison.",
          "word": "SLITHER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was defeated in his first attempt to be elected to the LEGISLATURE.",
          "word": "LEGISLATOR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The PARALLEL streets crossed just north of the city.",
          "word": "PARALLEL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Her advice was so LOGICAL that we had to agree with her.",
          "word": "LOGICAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The kind old man tried to be FIENDISH to everyone he met.",
          "word": "FIENDISH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "When he became MONARCH he freed all the prisoners and declared a national holiday.",
          "word": "MONARCH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was knocked unconscious, and when he came to he couldn't RECOLLECT his name or where he lived.",
          "word": "RECOLLECT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The grownups listened politely while Jim sang, but his younger brother SNICKERED.",
          "word": "SNICKER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The mechanic's VERDICT was that our car was a total loss.",
          "word": "VERDICT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was a BARBARIC moment for him when he finally saw his parents after so many years.",
          "word": "BARBARIC",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Norma DAMAGED the radio when she dropped it.",
          "word": "DAMAGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were in a FESTIVE mood; they didn't stop celebrating until dawn.",
          "word": "FESTIVE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I am SUSCEPTIBLE of anyone who offers me that much money for so little work.",
          "word": "SUSCEPTIBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Pete DREADED having to decide which school to go to.",
          "word": "DREAD",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "CONTRACT",
          "answers": [
            "refusal",
            "agreement",
            "promise"
          ],
          "word": "CONTRACT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SLITHER",
          "answers": [
            "slip",
            "slump",
            "slide"
          ],
          "word": "SLITHER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LEGISLATOR",
          "answers": [
            "congressman",
            "policeman",
            "lawmaker"
          ],
          "word": "LEGISLATOR",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PARALLEL",
          "answers": [
            "corresponding",
            "unknown",
            "similar"
          ],
          "word": "PARALLEL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LOGICAL",
          "answers": [
            "hopeful",
            "reasonable",
            "understandable"
          ],
          "word": "LOGICAL",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FIENDISH",
          "answers": [
            "cruel",
            "strict",
            "evil"
          ],
          "word": "FIENDISH",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MONARCH",
          "answers": [
            "general",
            "emperor",
            "king"
          ],
          "word": "MONARCH",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RECOLLECT",
          "answers": [
            "recall",
            "think",
            "judge"
          ],
          "word": "RECOLLECT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SNICKER",
          "answers": [
            "chuckle",
            "smile",
            "giggle"
          ],
          "word": "SNICKER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VERDICT",
          "answers": [
            "judgment",
            "opinion",
            "punishment"
          ],
          "word": "VERDICT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BARBARIC",
          "answers": [
            "wild",
            "false",
            "uncivilized"
          ],
          "word": "BARBARIC",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DAMAGE",
          "answers": [
            "injure",
            "hurt",
            "stop"
          ],
          "word": "DAMAGE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FESTIVE",
          "answers": [
            "joyful",
            "merry",
            "tiring"
          ],
          "word": "FESTIVE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SUSCEPTIBLE",
          "answers": [
            "angry",
            "weak",
            "sensitive"
          ],
          "word": "SUSCEPTIBLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DREAD",
          "answers": [
            "shame",
            "fear",
            "terrify"
          ],
          "word": "DREAD",
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}